here's the homework problem as you know
last week
we caught a mistake with sal khan from
khan academy this week we found another
mistake from
another famous physics professor
his channel named professor dave
explains let's take a look he knows a
lot about the science stuff
if you compress the spring and put a
little 0.01 kilogram army guy on top
how high will it be launched when you
release the spring
and this is the answer as it happens we
could use
this same equation again and we could
plug in
our initial velocity as well as a final
velocity
of zero since velocity will be zero
at the moment that the object reaches
the peak
of the trajectory and we get 1.35 meters
this is wrong so i want you to
get the right answer